In hindsight, we accomplished what was required.
不久之前 我们力挽狂澜
With Unicron's awakening,
由于宇宙大帝的苏醒
extreme measures needed to be taken.
我们不得不采取非常手段
Enemies became allies,
与宿敌并肩作战
allies became confidants.
向同伴托付重担
And, with the Matrix of Leadership,
最终 借助领导模块的力量
the planet Earth was saved.
地球得以平安无事
Though at immeasurable personal cost...
但这却是以巨大的个人牺牲为代价…
When Optimus surrendered the Matrix
在擎天柱失去领导模块的同时
he'd lost more than the collective wisdom of the Primes.
也失去了历代领袖所积累下来的智慧
Who are they?
他们是谁？
Our mortal enemies!
是我们的死敌！
... He lost himself.
…他遗忘了自我
That doesn't follow.
这解释不通啊
Optimus knew Megatron!
擎天柱依旧认识威震天！
They were like BFFs!
而且好得就跟老相识一样！
If Optimus did not know his own name,
如果说擎天柱不记得自己的名字
perhaps it is because the title of Prime hasn't yet been granted to him.
也许是因为他当时还没有被选为领袖
- Huh? - What?
- 哈？ - 什么？
Say again?
再说一遍？
With the power of the Matrix no longer within him,
由于领导模块的力量不再护佑他
it would stand to reason that Optimus has reverted to his pre-Prime state:
理所当然的 他回到了成为领袖之前的状态：
the historical archivist, Orion Pax.
历史档案保管员 奥利安・派克斯
You mean, in his mind.
你是说 他是这么认为的
Are you telling me Prime thinks he is some kind of librarian and a Decepticon?!
你是说他现在是个图书管理员 而且是个霸天虎？！
Attention, crew.
全体船员注意
Our guest is currently in isolation,
我们的贵客目前尚须独处
to help ease his transition.
以适应新的环境
But when Orion Pax emerges,
当你们见到奥利安・派克斯时
he is to be shown every courtesy.
必须以礼相待
And the first to address him as "Optimus Prime" will have his voice-box torn out.
如果有人胆敢称呼他“擎天柱” 那我会揪出他的扬声器
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
Is it wise, to allow an Autobot, current or former,
无论如何 任由一个前任汽车人在这里晃荡
full run of the premises?
这明智吗？
Nothing happens aboard this ship without my knowledge.
这艘船上的任何风吹草动都逃不过我的眼睛
You will do well to remember that, Airachnid.
你最好牢记这一点 毒蜘蛛
But there's no need for concern.
不过没什么好担心的
Orion does not possess the same fight Optimus is so renown for.
奥利安并不像擎天柱那般骁勇善战
Then what use is he to our Cause?
那他对我们有何用？
Ah, rest assured, Orion Pax will indeed earn his stripes.
啊 放心吧 奥利安会证明自己的价值的
Welcome back to the winning team.
欢迎回归胜利之师
Being a Decepticon is a choice, Agent Fowler.
是否成为霸天虎需要做出选择 福勒探员
One that I have a hard time believing Optimus would make at any point in his life.
我绝不相信擎天柱会在有生之年做出这样的决定
So, if he's riding with the 'Cons...
所以 如果他和虎子们狼狈为奸…
... it's because Megatron is working some kind of voodoo.
…肯定是威震天给他灌了某种迷魂汤
Orion Pax may not currently be an Autobot up here,
奥利安・派克斯也许现在不知道自己是汽车人
but I must believe, he will never stop being one in here.
但我坚信在他的内心深处 绝不会放弃追逐理想
We must locate him to know for certain.
我们必须找到他来确认这点
Hold up. I have a chip lodged in my behind that let's Uncle Sam know
等等 山姆大叔在我背上装了块芯片
when I stop for donuts.
以防止我开小差
Are you telling me you can't just track Prime?
难道你们就没办法追踪到擎天柱了？
Optimus's signal has not reappeared since he embarked for Earth's core.
擎天柱的信号自他进入地心后就再也没出现过
But we must get to work finding him.
但我们必须全力去找他
If we have any hope of initiating his contingency plan.
如此一来 我们还是有机会启用应急方案的
Contingency plan?
…应急方案？
What "contingency"?
什么应急方案？
Is that even a word?
那只是个词吗?
The Key card!
是钥匙芯片！
So, what's it do?
好吧 它是做什么用的？
It grants access to Vector Sigma,
用来启动魔力神球
the repository of the wisdom of the Primes.
历代领袖的智慧宝库
Is that some sort of supercomputer?
那是一种超级计算机么？
So, we can just download Optimus's memories back into him?
那么 我们只要把擎天柱的记忆重新下载一遍就行了？
Great! Which one is the big V?
太棒了！这个大球在哪儿？
Over here? Somewhere in back?
这个？还是后面哪个？
Vector Sigma is more than a "supercomputer", Jack.
魔力神球可不光是一个“超级计算机”杰克
It is an ancient source of mystical power.
它是一种神秘力量的古老源泉
On Cybertron.
在塞博特恩上
You had been a captive of the Autobots and locked in stasis for quite some time, Orion.
汽车人俘虏了你 并让你一直处在休眠状态 奥利安
Long enough for us to be in exodus on another world.
在这期间 我们已经流亡到了另一个世界
Exodus? Why?
流亡？为什么？
Because the Warlord Ratchet's careless actions
都怪大军阀救护车的鲁莽行径
led to this.
导致了这一切
Ahhh...
啊…
... Cybertron!
…塞博特恩！
Jackson Darby! You will NOT be travelling to another planet.
杰克逊・达比！不许你到外星球去！
I'm in!
那我去！
You're not going either, Miko.
你也不能去 神子
Not when one of YOU can.
你们谁都不许去
June's right.
琼是对的
Why send a boy to do a bot's job?
为什么要派一个男孩去做一个汽车人的工作？
Because only a Prime can access Vector Sigma.
因为只有领袖才能启动魔力神球
Or one chosen by a Prime.
或者领袖钦点之人
Optimus gave the Key card to Jack.
擎天柱把钥匙芯片交给了杰克
It is now imprinted with his unique biosignature.
它已经匹配了他独有的生命特征
So, you mean Jack's like some kinda honorary Prime?
那么你的意思是 杰克算是名誉领袖了？
Let's just say, Jack is the only one who can return Optimus to the Autobot we knew.
直说吧 要想让擎天柱变回那个我们熟知的汽车人 只有杰克能做到
But why would Optimus willfully endanger a human? A child?
但为什么擎天柱故意置一个人类于险境？ 还是一个孩子？
I'm not a child, Mom!
我不是孩子了 妈妈！
Maybe Optimus believes there's more to Jack than meets the eye.
也许擎天柱相信杰克大有潜力可挖？
All of which is moot.
说这些都毫无意义
The Key-card is useless to us without the means of reaching Cybertron,
如果到不了塞博特恩 钥匙芯片对我们毫无用处
which we at present do not possess.
而现在我们却是一筹莫展
Dude. What about THAT?
伙计 那个怎么样？
Miko, the Ground bridge barely got them into Earth orbit, remember?
神子 环陆桥只能勉强送他们到地球轨道 记得吗？
Yeah, but Ratchet built it.
是啊 但是救护车造了这个
Can't he just turbo-charge the thing?
他就不能给这东西增强功率吗？
I cannot believe Ratchet capable of such horrors.
我不相信救护车会做出这么可怕的事情
Yes. And to think the Doctor of Doom's mad quest for power continues...
是啊 难以想象 放任这个江湖郎中追求权力会是什么后果
his marauders pursued us to this planet's orbit.
他的爪牙把我们驱逐至这个星球轨道上
We feel its species are not ready to behold us.
我们认为这星球上的物种还没准备好接受我们
But we have resolved to protect this world from the same tragedy which was dealt to our own.
但我们已下定决心保卫这个星球 以避免重蹈我们的覆辙
One question, Megatron.
我有一个问题 威震天
Why are we called Decepticons?
我们为什么被称作霸天虎？
Another craven Autobot scare tactic.
不过是汽车人的恐慌伎俩而已
The name was meant to demonize us.
用这个名字来妖魔化我们
Instead, we wear it as a badge of honour.
相反 我们将它视为荣誉的象征
For if speaking the truth is deception,
若追求真理被视作霸权的话
then we are gladly guilty.
那我们甘当此罪
Now please, Orion.
奥利安 别着急
There will be plenty of time for catching up.
还有很多时间给你补课
You must rest.
你现在得休息
Megatron!
威震天！
I will do my part to stop Ratchet's unspeakable crimes of aggression.
我会竭尽全力阻止救护车那罄竹难书的侵略暴行
This I vow. With all my Spark.
我以自己的火种起誓
It seems we have successfully achieved control of Orion's spark.
看来我们成功获取了奥利安火种的信任
Now, to put his mind to work.
现在要让他的脑子为我所用了
Have you sanitized the data-core?
你清理完数据核心了吗?
Excellent. Our new archivist will require unlimited access to our files.
很好 我们的新档案员可以随心所欲地浏览我们的文件了
It would be counterproductive for him to stumble upon any sensitive information.
若让他不巧撞见敏感信息 恐怕会带来不良后果
Two "body slamburger" specials. Enjoy!
两份“巨无霸汉堡”特色餐 请慢用！
Hey Jack!
嘿 杰克！
Sierra!
赛拉！
How come I never see you around?
怎么我最近一直没见到你？
What are you talking about?
你说什么？
We have chemistry together.
我们有化学反应的啊
Ehm, "class"! Chemistry class.
呃 化学课！我是指化学课
I mean, outside of school.
我是说 课堂以外的时候
I never see you at any parties or the mall.
我从来没在聚会上或是商场里看过你
Well, mostly I'm here, wearing the hat.
嗯 大部分时间我都带着帽子站在这里
And you never can study too hard for the old SATs, you know.
而且你也知道 准备变动指数考试得下相当的功夫
And, there's some other... stuff.
而且 我还有些别的…事情
Oh. Don't go anywhere!
噢！先别走！
Welcome to K.O. drive-in, may I take your...
KO汽车快餐欢迎您 请问您要点…
5 PM, Jack. Your shift is over.
五点了 杰克 你该下班了
Let's go.
我们该走了
Oh! That kind of... "stuff".
哦！原来是“这事”
Sierra, wait!
赛拉！等等！
She's my mother!
…她是我妈妈！
Your mom looks good in leather.
你妈穿皮衣真有型
On your bike.
还骑在你的摩托上
Didn't mean to decimate your social life.
我不是故意要毁了你的社交生活的
Not the first time.
又不是第一次了
Any sign of Optimus?
有擎天柱的消息了吗？
Not today.
暂时没有
Not yet!
只是暂时的！
When we stormed the Iacon Hall of Records in the winning days of the war for Cybertron,
当我们在塞博特恩内战中取得优势之时 我们占领了铁堡的档案馆
we acquired highly classified files.
从那里得到了一些高度机密文件
Files written with Autobot codes, which we had been unable to decipher.
这些文件被汽车人加密过了 我们无法破译
Autobot codes, which the Iacon archivist Orion Pax should have no trouble cracking.
汽车人的密文 对铁堡档案员奥利安・派克斯而言那是手到擒来啊
Considering what's at stake,
考虑到潜在的风险
shouldn't we beef up the security around here?
我们是不是该加强这附近的安保？
Knockout, I believe that Orion will perform most effectively
击倒 我倒认为奥利安需要一个完全不受威胁或拘束的环境
if he does not feel threatened or confined in any way.
才会有效地完成他的工作
However, it is no coincidence that Orion's work-station is located in direct proximity to the Energon storage vault.
当然 奥利安的工作室靠近能量储藏室绝非偶然
Which is under constant surveillance...
因为能量储藏室随时有人监管…
Well played.
…陛下英明
Ratchet! Are you turbo-charging the Ground-bridge?
救护车！你在增强环陆桥的功率吗？
Tinkering.
只是随便弄弄
No need to get anyone's hopes up, just yet.
不必抱太大期望
Orion! How fares project "Iacon"?
奥利安！“铁堡”计划进展得如何了？
I am a bit rusty, I fear.
恐怕我的技艺生疏了
I've only managed to decode three entries.
我只破译了三个条目
And what do these entries comprise?
都是些什么内容？
They were logged by Autobot archivist during the war after I entered stasis.
这些都是我在休眠期间的档案
My only knowledge of its content so far
我唯一了解的信息是
is that they are coordinates,
它们是坐标
targeting locations on this very planet.
目标地点正是这个星球
I surmise that they could indicate hiding places for vessels
我猜测 这些地方可能藏有塞博特恩的飞船
shuttled from Cybertron for safe-keeping.
用于保管某些东西
Such as historical documents or cultural artifacts?
比如历史文件或者艺术品？
My greatest fear would be weapons of mass destruction.
我更担心他们藏匿了大规模杀伤性武器
Hidden away for later use.
以便不时之需
All the more reason it is essential that we do everything in our power
那更说明我们得竭尽全力
to keep said vessels from Autobot reach.
阻止汽车人得到这些飞船
We are fortunate to have you on our side, Orion Pax.
能有你相助是我们的造化 奥利安・派克斯
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
I am puzzled by one particular finding.
有一个信息令我很困惑
I have discovered several historic references to Starscream as your second-in-command.
很多历史资料中提及您的副官红蜘蛛
Yet I have not seen him aboard the ship.
但我却没在船上看到他
Sadly, Commander Starscream is dead.
很不幸 红蜘蛛指挥官已经牺牲了
Orion asks many questions.
奥利安的问题太多了
A valuable trait in an archivist, but not in a Decepticon.
对一个档案员来说这是好品质 但作为霸天虎则不然
It is a matter of time before he unravels our fabrications
要不了多久 他就会识破我们的骗局
and his innate sense of right and wrong rises to the surface...
并重拾他与生俱来的是非观念…
I only hope that Orion will complete project "Iacon"
我只希望奥利安能完成“铁堡”计划
before I am forced to destroy him, once and for all.
在我干净彻底地 销毁他之前
Ratchet!
救护车！
You awake?
你醒了吗？
This is an emergency!
紧急情况！
Agent Fowler! Is it Optimus?
福勒探员！是擎天柱吗？
It's 'Cons!
是虎子！
And they're busting into the same military research lab they hit two months ago.
他们又闯进了两个月前他们袭击过的军用实验室
Another Space-bridge?
又想建太空桥了？
But for all we know Optimus is riding with them.
最重要的是擎天柱和他们在一起
Roll out!
出发！
Drop the power source!
放下动力装置！
Aren't you missing someone?
你们是不是缺个人？
Ready for that bridge!
把桥准备好！
We'll be sure to tell the big O you said "Hello".
我们一定代你们向柱子问好
Arcee!
阿尔茜！
Scrap.
见鬼
Where's Optimus?
擎天柱在哪儿？
Answer me!
回答我！
What?!
什么？！
Arcee...
阿尔茜…
Allow me to welcome her aboard.
让我来好好招待她
No! If Orion so much as lays eyes on another Autobot
不！别说当着奥利安的面摧毁一个汽车人
let alone be allowed to witness its destruction,
哪怕让他看到别的汽车人
everything he currently believes will be called into question.
都会让他对之前相信的事情产生怀疑
See to it that Arcee is escorted off this ship immediately!
立即确保阿尔茜被护送着离开这艘船！
Orion! Please return to your station.
奥利安！请回到你的工作站
Lord Megatron's orders.
这是威震天陛下的命令
I heard a commotion.
我听到了骚动声
What the...?
什么？
You weren't able to determine the Decepticons' location
你既没确定霸天虎的位置
or if Optimus was even aboard ship?
也不确定擎天柱是否在船上？
I... can't confirm.
我…不能确认
Bulkhead!
隔板！
What? You needed that?
干嘛！？那个你有用吗？
Only thing I need is our head honcho back!
我唯一需要的就是我们的头头回来！
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错
If any of us needed rescuing, Optimus would have found a way.
要是有人真心想救擎天柱 肯定会有办法
I didn't. Simple as that.
我没找到 就那么简单
Ratchet!
救护车！
What happened out there?
你们都做了什么？
Reports indicate at least a dozen wounded.
我接到报告说十多人受伤了
The hit's on me to provide some explanation.
这让我怎么去解释
You bots better get your act together or the Pentagon
你们干脆都回家去
But... where would you go?
那你们能去哪儿？
Who knows. Maybe they'll ship us out to some island
谁知道 也许他们会把我们用船运到某个岛上
or fire us into space!
或者是把我们送上太空！
Wouldn't that be a welcome relief.
我们倒乐得轻松
I don't blame Fowler!
我不怪福勒！
Optimus would have evacuated all humans in the area
要是擎天柱在 他会在与虎子交战之前
before engaging the 'Cons.
疏散那片区域的所有人类
We don't actually know what Optimus would have done because he's not here!
实际上我们才不知道擎天柱会怎么做 因为他根本就不在这！
You're pretty good at stating the obvious, Bulk.
你真会说废话 小隔
Anything else you'd like to mention that we already know?
能讲点我们不知道的吗？
Nothing I can say in front of the children.
在孩子们面前我没什么可说的
Hey! Aren't we overlooking one positive?
嘿！我们就不能看看积极的一面吗？
Nobody's talking about what the 'Cons just got their claws on.
没人注意到虎子们接下来要做什么吗？
Yes, we managed to allow them to finally
是啊 他们终于如愿以偿
acquire a power source for their space bridge!
得到了太空桥的动力装置！
And how exactly that would be a positive?
那怎么能算积极的方面？
We let them finish building their Space-bridge.
我们让他们造好太空桥
Why? So they can bring more zombies back from Cybertron?
为什么？好让他们把更多的僵尸 从塞博特恩带到这里来吗？
No. So we can commandeer it.
不 好让我们去接管它
And use it to send me to Cybertron.
用它把我送到塞博特恩去
Woah. That's a pretty good idea.
哇哦 那真是个好主意
Oh well.
噢 好吧
If Miko thinks it's a good idea...
如果神子觉得那是个好主意…
Nobody saying it will be easy but you've seized the Space-bridge before!
没人把它当成儿戏 但你们以前曾经夺取过太空桥！
We blew one up.
我们只是炸飞了一个
That's a whole lot different than seizing and holding one.
那跟夺取并控制一个是两码事
Bee's right. We have to find that thing first.
小蜂是对的 我们先得找到那玩意
Hellooo!
我说！
If it's a space bridge... isn't it?
要是太空桥的话 难道不应该在…？
The term "space" refers to its transport range,
“太空”指的是传送范围
not its physical location.
不是它本身的地理位置
And we've been monitoring Earth's orbit since the last one,
上次事件以后我们就一直在监控地球轨道
we'd know if it were there.
要是有太空桥的话我们会知道的
So, the Bridge could be somewhere right here on Earth?
那么太空桥可能就在地球上的某处？
Like trying to find a servo at a scrapyard.
这相当于在一个废车场里找一个涡轮机
Then maybe we better start looking.
那我们最好现在就行动
But the fact remains:
但现状没有改变：
We don't know what the Decepticons have in store for Optimus.
我们不知道霸天虎要对擎天柱做什么
Or if he's truly safe from harm.
也不知道他是否还健在
Starscream!
红蜘蛛！
That's "Commander Starscream".
是“红蜘蛛指挥官”
What's your malfunction?
你们短路了吗？
Lower those weapons immediately.
立刻放下武器
I'm sorry, Sir, but Lord Megatron ordered that you be taken into custody
对不起 长官 但是威震天陛下有令 如果你回到船上
should you ever return to the ship.
就立即将你逮捕
What?
什么？
Clearly, there has been a mistake.
显然 这中间有些差错
Lo!
看呐！
Optimus Prime?!
擎天柱？！